Welcome back to A-Push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. The 1950s and 1960s. There is a
big word I want to throw out there and
say, trust. Because these two eras of
American history saw many people trust
the American liberal government. And
now, I want to put it bluntly as we are
in the 70s, the optimism of the 50s and
early 60s is now gone. Vietnam is an
utter failure and causes people to
distrust the government. But then, the
truly infamous Watergate scandal
happens. Where President Richard Nixon
covers up a burglary at the Democratic
National Committee headquarters,
revealing widespread illegal
surveillance and political sabotage,
leading to Nixon's presidential
resignation in 1974. And not to mention,
the 1970s American economy had high
inflation and growing unemployment,
which is a very rare economic phenomenon
called stagflation. When we get into
Jimmy Carter's presidency, it doesn't
get much better. The energy crisis moves
into full effect, a hostage crisis in
Iran made the government appear
ineffective. And now, by this point,
distrust in the United States government
by its own citizens is at an all-time
high. The liberals in society have
dominated the political landscape for so
long now, dating all the way back to the
New Deal. But now, with this combination
of things, conservatives are going to
rise through the cracks. Conservatives
will have an ideology of thinking the
government is way too big, so they want
less regulation, a stronger military,
and a pushback to traditional values.
Not to mention, you also see a rise of
evangelical Christianity, which will
become more intertwined with politics,
specifically intertwining with the
conservative side. This will lead to the
80s later, where conservatism will take
over. On the screen now are AP-style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
Thank you all for watching Unit 8. I
will see you in Unit 9.